I always say I should scrap DSE.  In Hong Kong I think we are
very backward, because however now driving is not riding a
carriage
responsibility waiting for exercise, or taking the initiative to do something you are not a
I walk I count can so say I do not see the I
see howtoachieve.  I am already doing my best to
parallel the needs of the various street levels.  Clearly the government leads the
company as well, there are many things you want to do, but you may not
you do it There are some things you do not want to do, you have no way to refuse
How important do you think the Abilitya leader?  This
guy engaged but open week do not do this
feed you busy, on the factory your heart has officially logged into
Spotify and Apple
Podcast, want to listen to this version of anytime,
click the link below, also want your heart D
will only be loaded in 2.0, remember to
subscribe to your son 2.0!
Welcome to watch on your heart, today we invite yeah!
Ha, actually, I have many times before I want to find you to
talk, because actually we have hit several times, my
first encounter is in the booke, so that time
, I sat down to talk for almost half an hour, I have
learned a lot, so then there are many different large
events we have hit, then I remember is and
talked to you two words yeah so.  In fact, I think about your I
think is very curious and unique before actually you have the
United States when, growing up when you worked as an architect and a
teacher, and someone offered you as a principal, so
after you finished the freemarket, you Wei Ran
went to the government for such a large organization for more than
ten years  There will be
different experiences through different experiences, because in
fact, I as an entrepreneur, and we have many
audiences, may be in large institutions to do this,
to face many views of the system, and at the same time it may have
a very reminiscent of influence, very wanting
impact.  Exactly how can you
balance these two things, how is a large
organization, actually from your experience what you will see
, or have some learned tricks can be given to our
audience.  There’s no morning math, like you said, which means
I’ve been through a lot of different things, but I guess for myself
?  The main thing is to keep choosing like this. You
like to do those things.  Well, it's a bit arbitrary.  Do you
know a person who does my best, you think.  It can be
said that you can do something like to do what you want to do
, but sometimes some work environment may not
allow you to do such things, for example, in the government there
, you have many things you want to do, but you may not allow
you to do it, there are things you do not want to do you can not
refuse so you have to, find a balance that is not
all, is not able to find a balance
Able to be all packaged like that.  May I gossip about
inthelifeofsir?  In fact, you
now you live is it, your state this this time
period of you, how much of your time putting work,
how much of the whole time putting on live.  But I like to
mix both things, I get up early for breakfast
time I follow Shen Wan, I I have not seen those, because
those emails, WhatsApp,
WeChat and other things.  So just come out and see where there is a meeting
, here I do two or three times a week, so then
mostly will make some friends.  Have a drink.  Every day is a bit
different, that is, every day is different, it is different.
And you enjoy this kind of irregular
schedule, I do not like
regular things, but that is not very
enjoy irregular so I can
hardly say.  But that you have black that stuff this I
resisted.  I see you continue to have said to fine turn
education this thing so, I think actually
in the early years has f to your mind.  This this
has because nowadays our class you and you look back at
those photos um.  It's not much different hmm.  So especially
in Hong Kong here, I think we are very happy later,
that is, a lot of things are very 19th century, that is, however, driving a
car is not riding a horse-drawn carriage, really to my so-called called heavy
, you are to Imagine and think about how this should be
.  Before you joined the government, did you start to
notice that you had an
entrepreneurial
mindset?  I don't think so that we
grew up in the, 70s those people do not like and smell that kind of
things, so I'm in school too, I'm
architecture, which is almost half of fine arts yeah, science yeah
things, so I think it's a pretty good balance
, suddenly there's an opportunity to say that in the wave of teachers so tried to establish the school.
So to write their own course so, they think I write the course
very so ah become the whole market, I am responsible for all his course
design that things, so those done for several years so you then that
make the goods that, you did not throw something from the time very
different some new practices, so that they feel very
effect so.  So at that time I thought the most important thing was that it was
about communication.  And in you say immigrant students
and
local students this the most important thing is to look back at
their own values ​​is how to clear, so at that time I in many of those courses there this into a lot of so-called u clarification, because if you learn something, you still do not know where your values
, so actually these things come to us today when we talk about AI
, these are the most important things on, in fact, it is not
those
things in the courses.  I do not know
this, actually related to sometimes I am in the company
, may want to profile some
training for some colleagues.  But I have tried
this, in fact, if it is very single straight into the way out of
this, we may not enter or we may not be confused as to why it concerns
me.  So if it is not
established by that time, actually it continues to
sound this, that absorbing affection actually drift so
I do not know that you say that kind of this that means to
or may be making it that cognitive that
open, actually doing this one thing can be
said so, because actually it is your most to this one thing this is can
make you want those people say you want to say that you want to say something in the
past.  But you
are able to find different ways that
they are able to tell that back to you.  Well,
so you are in school, actually you have tried how to
design a um, then have real money
, can communicate with some different people
, actually do
quite well.  But there are people offer long jobs
for you, so you were then can you can not
bring us back when your teacher, is why not
continue this so actually I was in
Po Li School there, teaching
curriculum
development, that is, many things have been
done for several years, not very long.  Doing open
unhappy way than when you were building.  Happy OK?
Happier, because of contact with many young people.  There are more
days.  The part you enjoy comes from the
influe or the financial outcome of the study too
.
Or is it me, I think all of it, because from ah from doing a
failed architecture to start teaching have a stable life,
and there moved to work in the city's curriculum design, salary is jumped
several times so that of course there is OK, but then
I was in publicschool almost the
most senior that Asian came, but did scare, so he
found a new that I wanted to do it
.  So then I decided to take a
break, that is now do not know what to do.  So
I took the exam so in that period just got to know Ren
Quan, so he mentioned otherwise, for example, can take the exam in Hong Kong as an
AO.  So at that time I was interested in Asia, I was in
Asia too.  When I got a few jobs, I finally
chose to go to the Hong Kong government.  So actually your past
is your own profit and loss my choice I pay my own bill.  So that's what you
explain to yourself, but when you go to a make an
announcement is every decision you make you have to
explain to 7 million people right.  Why put myself in a
I think it was an attempt for me to come, um
into the government, my first job was in Shatin there one that, that
director, so it was responsible for the whole community of relations yeah, those
things, getting to know a lot of those things, learning a lot better,
reaching out to a lot of different people.  Yeah, that's interesting.
So working there is about a year or two, so
my next job is at the branch to be responsible for dividing
money for meat and this one eh Social.  So also worked for
a year so smoothly, so I did so he transferred me to do this
management
accounting,
so then this turn so and he transferred to
services there, so they entered the commission when I entered the
securities there
to do
protectioninvestors
.  I saw you transferred many times and looked back those were passive
transfers people said you went there, or still you applied back it
.  have.  There is no application for it is where there is a need to have to
switch so do not switch to the frame I heard this, in fact, you have a lot of
descriptions you were
public some jobs when, in fact,
this a lot from I have new things to play
Those that will definitely have frames, but you will
not say it is obvious to say, because each of you make a
certain decision is included values ​​there, because you decide
a good range of so you choose here ah or
choose here to return, choose the middle this is your choice at the time
.  Do you have a constant to try it, I see you have a lot of
different turn slow which
position to think is enough, since then this is my
mission, is there such a turn no no no no no no
, that is all I am in the moment now
hold moment is what I want to do something, I do, that is like now here
, I am suffering from talking to you here.  It's like what's going on in
this moment, then I
'll do something else.  OK, okay,
sorry a little.
Card day.  Yes, I need a.  I wonder when you worked
, so actually you can make your own profits and losses in the private market and be
responsible for it, but when you go to the
public, when you go to work, in fact,
every decision you make will affect millions of people.
But when you have to expect this one measure to be heard by the public,
you will be able to anticipate so many different
opinions, there will be different opinions
.  So what about us in those ten
years?  Yeah, what's lucky?  that is?  The every year has, every
year can also, every year can also be reduced.  And at that
time, I was on average this every year that expenditure increased by
one percent more, but this is not easy to say, that
is, you have to do a lot of preparation, you have to go to design a lot of things yeah
so yeah d while will do something, but you a lot of things, you are
not necessarily is speaking out that communication there this you are doing a
kind of called expectation
um to manage that sometimes how you are
More or less, that is, so that he has an anticipation or give
him a surprise, so many of these things are, in that
consideration.  What do you think in terms of anticipation?  In fact,
what is the most important thing to do?  To know
what they really need is to get off the ground, much better things are to get
off the ground, that is, initially say that things are going beyond their
expectations for the month or going below their expectations, to
.  The beauty of the time this slowly this reaches their expectations that month
yeah so, that is a lot of these things can be planned,
however it is is needs to be good.  So much better planning can be
done.  You think right when you enter the government
, to go with so many people to mouth pain has a
shock beginning a bit, but I, I feel that
I am
doing it with my heart, that is, with my own that is sincere to them
is saying your words you know what you know, you
are saying these in the community there, that is
how we can help him a lot
They mean later that life, so that means real students to
tell them and many of them some citizens actually generally this is
good
, so you if you are sincere that sit down and tell him, really can
not get those things they want, or get how much
part of these things, they are satisfied, they are
, but it is very good that it really needs you
Sit them all face to face and say so yeah so this is, this
is the important part.  Because this one show, called
on the creation of the body and mind, there are actually many, many viewers
, may be initial entrepreneurs, even in a large organization
may leadershiprow,
if they have some within the company some very important
decisions.  affe is all the
team, and those things, maybe a new
policy new rules, if not
good communication then, in fact, we you submit rules, we will
not like it, so there is actually a
project before it is to be done?  Or how should that communication actually be
cut open to be done most?
Actually I think the important thing, that I do this myself
is that transparency that is a lot better.  That everyone can
share.  Transparency means that you as a
leader that logic that
decision process is exactly how to
go.  Positive thinking is it, I'm thinking what how to it to
deal with?  These things so, if that's how it's done, how many options do I have
, um this option on
there how would it affect, why would I choose this
option it doesn't, so there's a cost
benefit thing there.  For example, your alone
company or this you alone to community
its such information, you can not say every one to talk
to you, how do you manage
these.  Look at it, so it is possible that you have to
everyone in the to the, there everyone say once, they can have
QandA yeah and so on, you can also be separate how
many yourself early to go to live your things yeah.  Is there an
example of you, actually yourself on top of it,
internally you and your team
may be there one, you have an objective
, you want to al everyone's, and you initially thought the department of
completed through a good.  I was on a
structure there this has setup a lot of these
things, I was, I was every Friday to catch
the exchange the CEO, the chairman of the SFC this the
president of the HKMA that what happened this week?  Let's
follow the week, what are we going to do, do we need
some banks or some a
capitalization,
because these and these money have to balance yeah so, so what special things do I have
?  I can slowly enter there, in the
structure there will not specifically say suddenly ļ all of
you these people so we will have an expectation that you are something
special so, so if you set
up in the structure there is already all
these things exist you can choose that time and that
fa how to mind those things into there.  Well
, in addition to having different departments, that is, the giants so there will be
an et.  So maybe you have to turn to
some of your conclusions in the meeting, some of your observations, turn to your own
internal team, so is there a need to go
up again?  I give a lot of
those supervisors to decide, because they themselves are most
familiar with what they look like there, and we are used to
such things, so that I also have different things in mind at different times
, they will understand you think in addition to
transparency, just now you named the same is
not the second.  I think ity, that is yourself is that is
genuinely he has done something, you do not think is very hypocritical
to deceive him or that people also understand your people, is also
a comparison line.  How do you build this
, is it that I can do this to you as soon as I know you?  Also when
you must be at different times you have this performance, to
many things to repeat repeated repeated many times before you can
do, like we taught at that time said everything you
have to say at least three times first, your students may not be able to grab what
you want to say, so you but you have said in different ways.
Actually this I I can quite
relate to this, because I started the company
almost three years or so, but I always this and when we come and
talk, I can not inspire each other's
.  There are even some commands, I have to go to such a way, I
can call it, there are many different books have said,
in fact, if you want to establish it,
sincerity is very important, not a
great effort, once the destination is good the difficulty
is you since you show up every day when you have not
violated, that is, what you said, you will do, in fact, are
daily system ah.  It's a
life, it's not a
task.  Is there any behavior that you think
is more outstanding fromus
.  This one has one thing сни let people feel it.
It's a down-to-earth person, that is, speaking to others.  I like to
see the field, I like to be on the street.  At that time you can eat,
you game yard there driving borrow and eat yeah so that that is these such
things can be relayed and that that
is not once, in this time, you are people know
that you are this kind of people.  Have you observed
that, in fact, the average person will tick quite a long time before they will believe that you
are an apprentice, and then it will be different or that person
, if you are a skeptical person,
you may never accept this one thing, but
some people would like to be able to integrate, that is, there in your world
, so very soon will accept those.  Well,
I hear it is to be transparent, to be sincere
eh also I am observing the most and finally there is a third thing, because
when you are very transparent this you open your
upforaccountability
.  How important do you think accounil is in doing something or
being asaleader?  This is
inevitable that is inevitable, and that you are to support that
responsibility, and that you are actually the worst of this is not
my business I do
not do this thing, because you yourself because your
decision is yours, you decide you are asking him to do a lot of things, so so
the responsibility should be yours, so there is something that
happens, you should change your own anger  This this that this
inevitable frame must be so people do things.  Doing
everything this one thing is important.  I found this, in fact,
you just said the description seems very straightforward and simple, but the
more people working in a large company this they will be for the
result for the result and untable,
they will for the middle of those, those
procedures to able, meaning
what does it mean?  Maybe he will say, "W opened this meeting,
check, but he may not say that I have through this meeting
, he achieved this meeting itself to achieve that result
. That is like said done yeah yes done so
what else do you want me to do, but actually the pointof that
meeting is to build into a result, he did not carry to
say, however that big corporate body inside I do
not know
Large machines have a distinct hierarchy and
high and low, in fact, the more will foster such a tendency goods
or mentality, so, in fact, I do not know my survival
, many people are such a mentality, is there anything that
can break this mind?  The
officer is not the same as the government company, it must have some different
procedures must follow these such
baths, that you slowly this every step of this way to do
up, so can do it, but you that as a
collar, you I think that responsibility should be in you there
um because especially the government there you, said a
policy so many many steps there, but the
Secretary is not received
, so you received the goods after out the scolding if so
actually you have to pay that responsibility is my good experience, in
fact, this one thing is from down has to be so because we have with
many large organizations when this, open I will find this, is
I will ask OK this project we will
want to achieve what landscape, or what standards we see
Type organizations, often they are not very mouth vote when I have no
opinion is or is helping yeah, help but in the middle is no
purely really hope you help help also there are many times
this is ah, we handed something to the customer, and
then he may not go to give a stark indicator that
he has to take back up to the department and then retreat maybe 15
people.
Department, and will have their own individual views, and his
views, is not a
standard, they are simply ah,
my job today is to, let's say, so he may be
based on not knowing what the machine bottom, let
these two sentences collected, and turned back to us to the middle of the
opponent, he may have some information
Ten, what is this one trying to achieve what
object frame how large organizations
often appear these such natural things, but
maybe in large organizations, he may not be the leader
so he actually has some chochance
choice
, I still say the flowchart out of so
in your flowchat there, I will know
that it is every different stage, you are some have some
achievements you can walk it walk
stage there, this sentence, we are here, we are
going to which one, what is done ah, so I have
one, I have my own monitoring
system
After every week on I may not, but because we hope he
has his own initiative he has to go
setup him there that things, or my own
workflow and his view is a bit different
, but that he goes to eventually there this will have a
convergence is there so, so it has to
do more preparation when
you get into the initial roll
That the biggest constraint is what I
look at things on I do not look at it Um I look at how
to achieve this, that is, if I want to
do something I how to do it to do this one thing, so it
starts to rule how to
bring this one thing
, how to go that is how to
deal with it
You are a?
But there is no way, I can say to write out to you
, so I think there is no such thing
left from the government do the announcement it
Naturally, that are those to help Um, we have to the
concept, we want to do this, so as much as possible to push out the body how
much support, that every time to do it have to see where there are
sponsors to do these things, because we
did not try to go shallow ourselves, um, so so it is the whole model is different
, but that do, I also do a lot of different
charity work, but that
really makes you excited
thing?  I've
learned a lot, that is, I follow what I do, so
after a period of time, I came out, I thought, I do I do
something in the future, there must be 3 different conditions
A subversion of um
Is that is it good wow dayone luckone
actually has popup, things actually carried actually
you more than ten years in the government when this one you have not
completed get yeah or yeah you in that institution actually you have a
longer beautiful can see the macro demand so so
you get out when you want to be in these other scare development
lop it is how three things develop out of politics
The government there something I put down the frame so I also do not have a
view of things that can be
connected together into a big thing out, not so the way
to see
this one thing, so they use a
technology approach, so it will subvert the whole
To do, that they then I think the biggest problem initially
out this is what is virtual insurance is it who knows
what is the pot this so, so if to know it, to people have
confidence in this, to trust,
um, so I was that to release a lot of their own videos
yeah, so that people that at least some people will get to know me or OK a lot of me to
do it
Attention you think is more important or that person is more important look is
important, I have also read people's
ideas have to, that things are not necessarily to be good
ech, but that is that person, his that
heart is there, is actually that is not
so difficult for me to see it like a little red
There are ideals, but in fact there is a hole in the middle of some such moderation
Actually I want to
have a small life, that process this is in our society
where this is sowing um
life. So I also think a lot of things have to change,
so now are still doing education there, because education there that is
too big, and AI for you almost night
but this is something that someone is excited about, you can
learn there are some new things, there can be pursued most seek
more new things
The kids take the 21st century right, this set of
education is already it
This, that is, of course, their way of accepting the model of doing things
is very different, so-called that they
know how to play i frame at the birth of digitales
, so many of these are is different so to that
, the model to change you, you think the
current European line left education
system
Days talk should abolish DS, because people have to take a good
DSE so that some many students to form
three so, it has stopped interested in anything
, always there νη how can he do better in
DSE there, um, so it becomes lost a lot of opportunities,
and the children at this age, that is, they should
absorb a lot of um, so it should be a lot of them
Happy growth, that is, that time is also important
so you have to be controlled by this one thing, and DSE
is a very low-level cognitive thing
, you can not be so that it can make a small thing can
play and can be able to learn it and in history in folklore
in learning or in life how can we put those things together,
because there is no pure thing in the world is not
biology
Later, suddenly realized there is something called bio right
so magical so this, that often the whole DNA is talking about this
bio of things, because we learn only purely
biology purely chemistry so
now even more sharp so many of your sociology things
and some science things can actually be combined  In the
future?
Things are de yeah these things, in fact, none do not know it, do not know
it so you so why say we ten start
9 not good, so actually many of them do not say their
technical things not good, but in fact it
became the beginning of the company when it, is encountered a lot of
these problems here, that is, you come you you do not even ash there
You die
. I take the ST good la frame um
, exams are necessarily a way of not necessarily you alone
this person your potential can not see
much so, so the school will change these things, and
I believe the university that education model must also change,
because it is now so this can not be sustained to
replace too DSE
Um, it's not good, don't, that's embarrassing to go to protect or
learn, yes, my daughter looked at my people first I looked at
him very very hard they, in fact, they may not
like these things, when they do what they like to do
, do something happy, I think children scared  Go over the
book, is the author of the history of human power, he wrote the
21st century yeah classmate one of his concepts this is that when
AI comes this actually you learn whatever you can
get through it the second thing is actually he may place
the job he prints a picture
out to the meeting you every four years you reinvent yourself
once, your own skill, your mind because of the choice and what the
public may actually no longer study
Out of the workers on place  It
can be 400 words to tell you something
Way to app get the AI ​​there, so we have a
researcher ask, switch to the French beef model does not start high school to
study escort
way, France actually that kind of education, is it, there is a very young has
begun to teach you
just eat, you are, yes,
it taught you to know which good food
How does he screen ah how does he think ah this one thing, will it
In Hong Kong, I think it needs, there are many places that are
very interesting, some schools are a forest where children are
in the forest, living with teachers
, so he sees what trees so what does his trees do so you
can also start introducing a bit of this
whole bio environment in that
What, actually where can you teach, ah now
see a lot of new things, I have to do a lot of
reading, so that for that
contentarea this begins to have a preliminary
form so and then to talk to some people more yeah they go to see
these things that do yeah how, that is, that sentence slowly increase that
knowledge
This one aspect  A few more
days, and then he said, oh, because this, we still have
those days, I have to teach daughter, so because he is now a the
same is quite and, in fact, many people have been some
children is not going to feel the
education into things, is the
parents themselves to prepare so,
I see actually this one is already the
distrust of education to the
future
system has not been able to accept it
So, so there is such a trend  Bury
also many people see a lot more
corner free, online you study catch those things this, like you have to have
6 months in MT so to get a degree so many things to
online so what you can do is how
I have to go to this one thing, is so that more people can
benefit that the same thing, that in many people that say to to
grab talent, in fact you will have a lot of things from
home
are workfromhome, in fact, there are
many people are not in Hong Kong and Hong Kong people you do
not necessarily have to do in Hong Kong, can, is doing the second
thing so, now on the, now with the help of AI ball
, has not been a problem, distance is not
a problem
Immigrant family life
In fact, different generations are different
, also have to have a package, each small is different, so
you have to accept that, you accept their way of doing things,
you have to accept their music, you have to accept their culture
, because our company actually has several, so I actually
think quite of this one thing, I and you contact
this often have a project, and then I
need to do this
task you used to do
Do he does it right, but Jy they are going to ask why
do it, why is it me what has this big impact He does not
want noto that job, but he will not constantly
ask why why why why he wants to build a solid why he
can do it when he can
aim at that object to do, but it is easy to be
perceived as he wants to fight it with that so or you
say  At
that time, let's talk more about the other that is this and that and this thing about the
background um, when it takes what people to do, so why
is he a most suitable person so you
talk to some people who were born in the 90s may have, that is called it is possible to be somewhat
different so if you have to compile a 21st century survival
for modern children what do you
think?
Yes I write it, because that I may not really well understand
, that is now this generation of children should this, it is not
including more of those so-called og things, instead I think
in a lot of, that is not those cold knowledge such as
better, more in some soft skills, such as what
skills communication is such as cooperation.
Because actually this I, I have observed, actually J this
generation, they are very independent out of
these three things, relatively, they do not seem to have too much in his
formative years, and then dropped out of society when
they have a lot of different
technology that drives him to not have to
face that thing there,
but those are important to
play yourself
imaginary people are playing with you, but
are actually coming on their own, but in the real world
, they really have to cooperate um how to communicate with people
um and also to have that with your heart because when I was
talking to you, I had to hope to understand what you were trying to
talk about so, so these are all important to
you to find this guild
Division of time if to be so right tight these questions are will
compare is will be subject to you read from Hopefully, hopefully yes to
how those things are how is made of society is benefiting it
Listen to music. Um Chinese and English I listen to Um
Which things, I leave when I do not clear all I do not leave, and that
my countertop is really very clean, I really do not
put something full, some people like the whole table put all the
files, so I I have nothing, because
how you go to fdefine success I fine
success is equal to happy so if you that in the inside
or there is a thing
樣嘢就成功㗎喇。乜嘢會帶到俾你最大開心
呀而家？關係囉，屋企人呀關係呀朋友嘅關
係呀。
你覺得而家你最大嘅開心關係上呢？你係想
preserve?或者係更加豐富現有嘅
關係，還是，其實你lookingto擴
大你嘅關係。兩樣都會有嘅。會有，即係佢
好多係屋企人。同朋友啲關係，同埋即係將
來你係即係每一日不停，我都會認識新嘅人 '
s.
呢個係呀？你鍾意食。我唔鍾意食肥嘅。你
唔鍾意ỡ。我唔鍾意
咬口多啲，OK咁呢一個對你嘅意義係乜嘢
？習慣咯，同埋嗰個真係一個
comfort素嗰度，即係呢個就係。成
長嚟。都食好多嘅，但係你即係食咗嗰個係
有一個溫暖嘅感覺。好多謝曬阿今日專登上
嚟我哋上呢個節目喇咁，如果想翻阿呢佢其 There
must be an IG, every week, he will
write a Sunday will be out so if you want to see
, you can follow this IG
Thankyousomuch